Howells family. Howells family papers (MS Am 1784-1784.13): Guide.
Howells family papers,
- I. bMS Am 1784-1784.4: William Dean Howells collection
  - A. bMS Am 1784: Letters to William Dean Howells
    - 1. Letters to William Dean Howells, purchase
      - [H], [C]. 1 letter; 1900., (192)
      - Hachette, firm, publishers, Paris. 1 letter; 1883., (193)
      - Hale, Charles, 1831-1882. 17 letters; 1863-1865., (194)
      - Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909. 15 letters; 1869-1890 [n.d.]., (195)
      - Hale, Edward Everett, 1863-1932. 1 letter; 1917., (196)
      - Hallström, Per, 1866-. 1 letter; 1911., (197)
      - Hapgood, Isabel Florence, 1850-1928. 2 letters; 1895., (198)
      - Harben, William Nathaniel, 1858-1919. 3 letters; 1902-1910., (199)
      - Hardie, James Keir, 1856-1915. 2 letters; 1895-1896., (200)
      - Hardy, Arthur Sherburne, 1847-1930. 1 letter; 1894., (201)
      - Hardy, Thomas, 1840-1928. 5 letters; 1879-1912., (202)
      - Harland, Henry, 1861-1905. 5 letters; 1887-1902., (203)
        Harmsworth, Alfred Charles, viscount Northcliffe. See Northcliffe, Alfred Charles William Harmsworth, 1st viscount, 1865-1922.
      - Harper, Joseph Henry, 1850-. 6 letters; 1896-1919., (204)
      - Harper, Joseph Wesley, d. 1896. 6 letters; 1885-1887., (205)
      - Harper, firm, publishers, New York. 33 letters; 1886-1900., (206)
        No. 16 with a copy of a letter from G.S. Rowe of The Cincinnati Medical Journal Co. to Harper Bros.
      - Harris, Joel Chandler, 1848-1908. 2 letters; 1900 [n.d.]., (207)
      - Harrison, Constance (Carey) 1843-1920. 1 letter; 1885., (208)
      - Harrison, Jonathan Baxter, 1835-1907. 2 letters; 1881., (209)
      - Harte, Bret, 1836-1902. 12 letters; 1869-1874 [n.d.]., (210)
        No. 10 publ. in Geoffrey Bret Harte, The letters of Bret Harte, p. 70-71.
      - Harvard College Board of Overseers. 1 letter; 1868., (211)
        Signed by Thomas Hill and John Langdon Sibley.
      - Harvey, George, 1864-1928. 2 letters; 1900-1908., (212)
        No. 1 signed by another hand.
      - Haweis, Hugh Reginald, 1839-1901. 6 letters; 1885., (213)
      - Hawthorne, Julian, 1846-1934. 1 letter; 1903., (214)
      - Hay, John, 1838-1905. 62 letters; 1861-1905 [n.d.]., (215)
        No. 19 with letter from Green Berry Raum to John Hay.
        No. 42 by another hand.
        Nos. 5, 7, 10, 13, 17, 22, 25, 26, 37, 38, 40, 41 publ. in William Roscoe Thayer, The Life and letters of John Hay.
      - Hayes, Rutherford Birchard, pres. U.S., 1822-1893. 29 letters; 1875-1889., (216)
        Nos. 1 and 3-29 with typed copies.
        Nos. 3, 11, 28, 29 in Charles Richard Williams, ed., Diary and letters of Rutherford Birchard Hayes.
      - Hayne, Paul Hamilton, 1830-1886. 2 letters; 1870-1872., (217)
      - Hendrick, Ellwood, 1861-1930. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (218)
      - Henschel, Sir Georg, 1850-1934. 3 letters; 1884-1916., (219)
      - Herne, James A., 1839-1901. 9 letters; 1889-1895 [n.d.]., (220)
        No. 5 with note from William Dean Howells to Joe [].
      - Herrick, Robert, 1868-1938. 2 letters; 1909., (221)
      - Hertz, C.L.I. 1 letter; 1882., (222)
      - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911. 29 letters; 1866-1909., (223)
      - Hildreth, Richard, 1807-1865. 3 letters; 1862-1864., (224)
        No. 2 with note by C.G. Hildreth.
      - Hill, Thomas, 1818-1891. 1 letter; 1867., (225)
      - Hillard, George Stillman, 1808-1879. 1 letter; 1867., (226)
      - Hinkson, Katharine (Tynan) 1861-1931. 1 letter; 1910., (227)
      - Hoar, Ebenezer Rockwood, 1816-1895. 1 letter; 1873., (228)
      - Holland, Josiah Gilbert, 1819-1881. 2 letters; 1879., (229)
      - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894. 58 letters; 1866-1894 [n.d.]., (230)
        No. 22 publ. in John T. Morse, Life and letters of Oliver Wendell Holmes, v. 2, p. 43.
      - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1841-1935. 1 letter; 1861., (231)
      - Holmes, Raymond. 1 letter; 1880., (232)
      - Hoppin, Augustus, 1828-1896. 3 letters; 1871., (233)
      - Houghton, Henry Oscar, 1823-1895. 4 letters; 1880-1885., (234)
      - Houghton, Richard Monckton Milnes, 1st baron, 1809-1885. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (235)
      - Hovey, William Alfred, 1841-1906. 1 letter; 1887., (236)
        Howard, Blanche Willis. See Teuffel, Blanche Willis (Howard) von, 1847-1898.
      - Howard, Bronson, 1842-1908. 3 letters; 1886-1899 [n.d.]., (237)
      - Howard, Oliver Otis, 1830-1909. 1 letter; 1875., (238)
      - Howe, Julia (Ward), 1819-1910. 7 letters; 1903-1909 [n.d.]., (239)
      - Howes, Annie G. 1 letter; 1881., (240)
      - Howitt, William, 1792-1879. 2 letters; 1876-1877., (241)
      - Hughes, Rupert, 1872-1956. 1 letter; 1919., (242)
      - Hurd, Melancthon M. 13 letters; 1866-1907., (243)
      - Hutchinson, Thomas, 1856-. 1 letter; 1899., (244)
      - Hutton, Laurence, 1843-1904. 2 letters; [1883]-1890., (245)
      - Irving, Sir Henry, 1838-1905. 9 letters; 1884-1895., (246)
      - Irving, Laurence, 1871-1914. 3 letters; 1909 [n.d.]., (247)
      - Issaverdens, Giscomo. 7 letters; 1874-1902 [n.d.]., (248)
      - Jackson, Frances Manette. 1 letter; 1898., (249)
      - Jackson, Helen (Fiske) Hunt, 1831-1885. 1 letter; 1881., (250)
      - Jackson, Jennie. 1 letter; 1865., (251)
      - James, Henry, 1811-1882. 4 letters; 1878 [n.d.]., (252)
        With no. 4 is a round-robin greeting to Henry James, with painting by Elizabeth Boott and verses by Grace Ashburner. Signed by Henry James, William James, and others.
      - James, Henry, 1843-1916. 133 letters; [1867]-1915 [n.d.]., (253)
        No. 17 with letter from Alexandra (Leighton) Orr to Henry James.
        No. 29 incomplete.
        Nos. 6, 9, 16, 120 publ. in Leon Edel, ed., The selected letters of Henry James.
        Nos. 2, 11, 50, 54, 56, 61, 64, 70, 72, 74, 75, 79, 80, 81, 84, 105, 106, 120 publ. in Percy Lubbock, ed., The letters of Henry James.
        Number 53 noted as missing as of 1989 March 22.
      - James, Robertson. 3 letters; 1889 [n.d.]., (254)
      - James, William, 1842-1910. 13 letters; 1885-1910 [n.d.]., (255)
      - Janvier, Thomas Allibone, 1849-1913. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (256)
      - Jefferson, Joseph, 1829-1905. 2 letters; 1880-1895., (257)
      - Jersey, Margaret Elizabeth (Leigh) Child-Villiers, countess of, 1849-1945. 1 letter; 1883., (258)
      - Jewett, Sara. 3 letters; 1878-1881., (259)
      - Jewett, Sarah Orne, 1849-1909. 16 letters; 1871-1902 [n.d.]., (260)
      - Johnson, Clifton, 1865-1940. 1 letter; 1892., (261)
      - Johnson, Eastman, 1824-1906. 1 letter; 1901., (262)
      - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1853-1937. 4 letters; 1881-1883., (263)
      - Jones, Henry Arthur, 1851-1929. 11 letters; 1906-1907 [n.d.]., (264)
      - Jones, Mary Cadwalader (Rawle), 1850-1935. 2 letters; 1911., (265)
      - Jusserand, Jean Jules, 1855-1932. 1 letter; 1916., (266)
      - Kaneko, Kentaro, viscount, 1853-. 1 letter; 1886., (267)
      - Kemble, Frances Anne, 1809-1893. 34 letters; [n.d.]., (268)
      - Kendal, Margaret Shafto (Robertson) Grimston, 1849-1935. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (269)
      - Keogh, Martin Jerome. 1 letter; 1916., (270)
      - Kester, Vaughan, 1869-1911. 2 letters; 1904-1905., (271)
        No. 2 with a note by Jessie Jennings Kester.
      - King, Basil, 1859-1928. 2 letters; 1910-1913., (272)
      - King, Clarence, 1842-1901. 4 letters; 1871 [n.d.]., (273)
      - King, Grace, 1852-1932. 2 letters; 1896-1910., (274)
      - Kinney, Coates, 1826-1904. 3 letters; 1888., (275)
      - Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936. 4 letters; 1896-1904., (276)
      - Kirk, John Foster, 1824-1904. 2 letters; 1872-1885., (277)
      - Kirkland, Joseph, 1830-1894. 1 letter; 1888., (278)
      - Kohlsaat, Herman Henry, 1853-1924. 3 letters; 1893-1894., (279)
      - Kraus, Ignaz. 1 letter; 1899., (280)
      - Kravchinskii, Sergei Mikhailovich, 1851-1895. 3 letters; 1891., (281)
      - La Farge, John, 1835-1910. 3 letters; 1909 [n.d.]., (282)
      - Laffan, William Mackay, 1848-1909. 2 letters; 1883-1907., (283)
      - Langley, Samuel Pierpont, 1834-1906. 3 letters; 1884-1895., (284)
      - Larcom, Lucy, 1824-1893. 2 letters; 1876 [n.d.]., (285)
      - Lathrop, George Parsons, 1851-1898. 4 letters; 1877-1884., (286)
      - Lathrop, Rose (Hawthorne) 1851-1926. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (287)
      - Leffingwell, Albert, 1845-1916. 2 letters; 1887., (288)
        No. 2 with copy of letter from A. Leffingwell to [John P. Altgeld], Governor of Illinois. (4 Nov. 1886 )
      - Le Gallienne, Richard, 1866-1947. 3 letters; [n.d.]., (289)
      - Leslie, Miriam Florence (Folline) Squier, 1851-1914. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (290)
        Signed "Frank Leslie".
      - Limbach, Hermann. 1 letter; 1895., (291)
      - Lippincott, Sara Jane (Clarke) 1823-1904. 2 letters; 1890 [n.d.]., (292)
      - Lloyd, Henry Demarest, 1847-1903. 3 letters; 1895-1898., (293)
      - Lloyd George, Margaret (Owen) d. 1941. 1 letter; 1910., (294)
      - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924. 1 letter; 1890., (295)
      - Lomas, George Albert. 1 letter; 1880., (296)
      - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1882. 37 letters; 1866-1881 [n.d.]., (297)
      - Loose, Katharine Riegel, 1877-. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (298)
      - Lovell, John W. 3 letters; 1890-1891., (299)
      - Low, Will Hicok, 1853-1932. 1 letter; 1908., (300)
      - Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891. 46 letters; 1860-1891., (301)
        Nos. 1-3, 5, 7, 9, 10, 13-15, 18, 19, 21, 23, 26, 29, 32, 33, 37-39, 43, 46 publ. in Charles Eliot Norton, ed., The letters of James Russell Lowell.
        Nos. 6, 8, 20, 25, 36, 44, 45 publ. in M.A. DeWolfe Howe, ed., New letters of James Russell Lowell.
      - Lowell, John Amory, 1798-1881. 1 letter; 1870., (302)
      - Lucas, Samuel, 1818-1868. 1 letter; 1865., (303)
      - Lucy, Sir Henry William, 1845-1924. 1 letter; 1906., (304)
      - Mabie, Hamilton Wright, 1846-1916. 2 letters; 1895., (305)
      - McCarthy, Justin, 1830-1912. 4 letters; 1886-1889., (306)
      - McClure, Samuel Sidney, 1857-1949. 12 letters; 1890-[1910] [n.d.]., (307)
        No. 3 is an unsigned contract and is noted as missing as of 1987 March 31. No. 4 is a draft of a contract between S.S McClure and W.D. Howells.
        No. 6 signed by another hand.
      - MacDowell, Edward Alexander, 1861-1908. 2 letters; 1893., (308)
      - McDowell, Henry B. 1 letter; 1892., (309)
      - McGibeny, James B. 1 letter; 1899., (310)
      - McIlvaine, Clarence W. 6 letters; 1889-1890 [n.d.]., (311)
        Nos. 1 and 2 signed "Harper and Bros.".
      - MacKaye, Steele, 1842-1894. 1 letter; 1887., (312)
      - McKim, Charles Follen, 1847-1909. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (313)
      - Macnaughtan, Sarah, d. 1916. 2 letters; 1910 [n.d.]., (314)
      - MacQuoid, Katharine Sarah (Gadsden), 1824-1917. 1 letter; 1883., (315)
      - Mahan, Alfred Thayer, 1840-1914. 1 letter; 1909., (316)
      - Mallory, Marshall H. 2 letters; 1881-1884., (317)
      - March, George P. 1 letter; 1862., (318)
      - Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940. 3 letters; 1899-1916., (319)
      - Marlowe, Julia, 1865-1950. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (320)
      - Marshall, Archibald, 1866-1934. 1 letter; 1914., (321)
      - [Masson, David, 1822-1907.] 1 letter; 1862., (322)
        Unsigned.
      - Matthews, Brander, 1852-1929. 6 letters; 1893-1909., (323)
      - Mayer, Nathan. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (324)
      - Mead, Edwin Doak, 1849-1937. 1 letter; 1887., (325)
      - Mead, William Rutherford, 1846-1928. 1 letter; 1885., (326)
        Meader, Elizabeth C. See Walter, Helen.
      - Merrick, Leonard, 1864-1939. 3 letters; 1904-1914., (327)
      - Merrill, Stuart, 1863-1915. 2 letters; 1891-1900., (328)
      - Mettedaglio, A. 1 letter; 1865., (329)
      - Meynell, Alice (Thompson) 1847-1922. 2 letters; [1916] [n.d.]., (330)
      - Millet, Francis Davis, 1846-1912. 4 letters; 1882 [n.d.]., (331)
      - Mitchell, Edward Page, 1852-1927. 1 letter; 1908., (332)
      - Mitchell, Silas Weir, 1829-1914. 1 letter; 1883., (333)
      - Moran, Thomas, 1837-1926. 1 letter; 1883., (334)
      - Morris, Harrison Smith, 1856-1948. 1 letter; 1902., (335)
        With two typed copies.
      - Motley, John Lothrop, 1814-1877. 12 letters; 1862-1865., (336)
        Letter of August 28, 1862 has Motley's signature cut-out. [Reported by reader 2010 July 17].
      - Moulton, Louise (Chandler), 1835-1908. 5 letters; [n.d.]., (337)
      - Munsey, Frank Andrew, 1854-1925. 1 letter; 1894., (338)
      - Murphy, Lady Blanche Elizabeth Mary Annunciata (Noel) 1845-1881. 10 letters; 1880-1881 [n.d.]., (339)
      - Murphy, John S. 1 letter; 1916., (340)
      - Neal, David Dalhoff, 1838-1915. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (341)
      - Nelson, Henry Loomis, 1846-1908. 2 letters; 1895-1896., (342)
      - Nicholson, Meredith, 1866-1947. 1 letter; 1913., (343)
      - Nicolay, John George, 1832-1901. 1 letter; 1885., (344)
      - Noble, Edmund, 1853-1937. 1 letter; 1887., (345)
      - Norman, Sir Henry, bart., 1858-1939. 2 letters; 1882-1885., (346)
      - Norris, Frank, 1870-1902. 2 letters; 1889 [n.d.]., (347)
      - Northcliffe, Alfred Charles William Harmsworth, 1st viscount, 1865-1922. 1 letter; 1904., (348)
      - Norton, Charles Eliot, 1827-1908. 35 letters; 1867-1908., (349)
        No. 5 with typed copy.
        TS: *58M-14
      - Ogden, Rollo, 1856-1937. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (350)
      - Olmsted, Frederick Law, 1822-1903. 1 letter; 1880., (350a)
      - Ongaro, Francesco dall', 1808-1873. 2 letters; 1869-1870., (350b)
      - O'Reilly, John Boyle, 1844-1890. 6 letters; 1874-1883 [n.d.]., (351)
      - Orr, Alexandra (Leighton) 1828-1903. 5 letters; [n.d.]., (352)
      - Osgood, James Ripley, 1836-1892. 77 letters; 1861-1891 [n.d.]., (353)
        No. 33 (in an unidentified hand) is a copy of an agreement between Jas. R. Osgood and Co. and The Century Co. concerning the publication of a proposed series of papers on Italian cities. With a copy of a letter from W.D. Howells to J.R. Osgood.
      - Osgood, James R. and co., publishers. 3 letters; 1880-1885., (354)
      - Otis, Albert Boyd. 1 letter; 1889., (355)
      - Owen, Robert Dale, 1801-1877. 8 letters; 1873-1876., (356)
      - Ozmun, Clara G. 1 letter; 1900., (357)
      - Page, L.C. and company, inc., publishers, Boston. 1 letter; 1900., (358)
      - Page, Thomas Nelson, 1853-1922. 2 letters; 1902-1910., (359)
      - Page, Walter Hines, 1855-1918. 5 letters; 1894-1910., (360)
      - Paget, Violet, 1856-1935. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (361)
        Incomplete.
      - Paine, John Knowles, 1839-1906. 3 letters; 1874-1902., (362)
      - Palacio Valdés, Armando, 1853-1938. 19 letters; 1886-1917., (363)
        Nos. 1-15 publ. in Edwin H. Cady, "Armando Palacio Valdés writes to William Dean Howells," Symposium (May, 1948 ) p. 19-37.
      - Palfrey, John Gorham, 1796-1881. 2 letters; 1866 [n.d.]., (364)
      - Palgrave, Sir Reginald Francis Douce, 1829-1904. 3 letters; 1882 [n.d.]., (365)
      - Palmer, Courtlandt, 1843-1888. 1 letter; 1887., (366)
      - Palmer, George Herbert, 1842-1933. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (367)
      - Palmer, Lady Sophia. 4 letters; 1883., (368)
      - Parkman, Francis, 1823-1893. 6 letters; 1879-1885 [n.d.]., (369)
      - Parton, Fanny Fern. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (370)
      - Parton, James, 1822-1891. 18 letters; 1871-1890., (371)
      - Parton, N.W. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (372)
      - Payne, Daniel C. 2 letters; 1862., (373)
      - Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer, 1804-1894. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (374)
      - Pease, Edward Reynolds, 1857-. 1 letter; 1890., (375)
      - Pennell, Joseph, 1857-1926. 8 letters; 1882-1885., (376)
        No. 3 with typed copy.
      - Perry, Nora, 1841-1896. 1 letter; 1873., (377)
      - Perry, Thomas Sergeant, 1845-1928. 10 letters; 1877-1895., (378)
        Parts of nos. 2 and 4 publ. in Virginia Harlow, "William Dean Howells and Thomas Sergeant Perry," Boston Public Library Quarterly (Oct., 1949 ) p.135-150.
      - Phayre, John F. 27 letters; 1886-1909., (379)
        No. 21 with excerpts from a letter by Osgood, McIlvaine and Co. to [J.A. Heaton], and a copy of a letter from J.A. Heaton to Osgood, McIlvaine and Co.
        No. 22 with copies of two letters from W.M. Colles to Clarence W. McIlvaine.
        No. 23 with excerpts from a letter of Harper and Bros. to their London office.
        Phelps, Elizabeth Stuart, 1844-1911. See Ward, Elizabeth Stuart (Phelps), 1844-1911.
      - Phillips, Wendell, 1811-1884. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (380)
      - Phillpotts, Eden, 1862-. 16 letters; 1909-1912 [n.d.]., (381)
        No. 6 with copy of a letter from E. Phillpotts to The Bookman.
        No. 13 with typed copy of Phillpotts' poem "Welcome," dedicated to Samuel Langhorne Clemens.
      - Piatt, John James, 1835-1917. 6 letters; 1860-1911 [n.d.]., (382)
      - Poel, William, 1852-1934. 2 letters; 1884-1885., (383)
      - Pond, James Burton, 1838-1903. 3 letters; 1898-1900., (384)
      - Potter, Henry Codman, bp., 1834-1908. 1 letter; 1901., (385)
      - Powell, []. 1 letter; 1904., (386)
      - Premio-Real, José Antonio de Lavalle y Romero, conde de. 1 letter; 1879., (387)
      - Preston, Harriet Waters, 1836-1911. 11 letters; 1874-1880., (388)
      - Price, S.B. 1 letter; 1865., (389)
      - The Prince manufacturing co., New York. 1 letter; 1884., (390)
      - Proelss, Robert, 1821-1906. 1 letter; 1893., (391)
      - Pryor, Roger Atkinson, 1828-1919. 6 letters; 1887., (392)
      - Putnam, George Haven, 1844-1930. 1 letter; 1869., (393)
      - Pyle, Howard, 1853-1911. 21 letters; 1890-1895., (394)
      - Quincy, Edmund, 1808-1877. 2 letters; 1868-1872., (395)
      - Rava, Aristide. 1 letter; 1864., (396)
      - Redpath Lyceum Bureau. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (397)
      - Reed, []. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (398)
      - Reed, Thomas Brackett, 1839-1902. 1 letter; 1890., (399)
      - Reid, Whitelaw, 1837-1912. 13 letters; 1866-1908., (400)
      - Remington, Frederic, 1861-1909. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (401)
      - Rhodes, James Ford, 1848-1927. 2 letters; 1913., (402)
      - Rice, Allen Thorndike, 1853-1889. 1 letter; 1885., (403)
      - Rice, Cale Young, 1872-1943. 1 letter; 1910., (404)
      - Ridge, William Pett, d. 1930. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (405)
        Riggs, Kate Douglas (Smith) Wiggin. See Wiggin, Kate Douglas (Smith), 1857-1923.
      - Riley, James Whitcomb, 1849-1916. 5 letters; 1891-1915., (406)
        No. 5 signed by another hand.
      - Ritchie, Anne Isabella (Thackeray), lady, 1838-1919. 3 letters; [n.d.]., (407)
      - Roche, James Jeffrey, 1847-1908. 3 letters; 1891-1905., (408)
      - Roe, Edward Payson, 1838-1888. 1 letter; 1888., (409)
      - Rohlfs, Anna Katharine (Green) 1846-1935. 1 letter; 1890., (410)
      - Roosevelt, Theodore, pres. U.S., 1858-1919. 7 letters; 1890-1906 [n.d.]., (411)
      - Ropes, John Codman, 1836-1899. 4 letters; 1891., (412)
      - Rose, George Maclean, 1829-1898. 1 letter; 1879., (413)
      - Rosedale, Honyel Gough, 1863-1928. 1 letter; 1909., (414)
      - Saint-Gaudens, Augustus, 1848-1907. 10 letters; 1886-1906 [n.d.]., (415)
      - Salm-Reifferscheid-Dyck, Christine. 3 letters; [n.d.]., (416)
      - Salter, Mary G. 1 letter; 1887., (417)
      - Salter, William Mackintire, 1853-1931. 3 letters; 1887., (418)
      - Salvini, Tommaso, 1829-1915. 1 letter; 1885., (419)
      - Sanborn, Franklin Benjamin, 1831-1917. 1 letter; 1867., (420)
      - Sangster, Margaret Elizabeth (Munson) 1838-1912. 4 letters; 1873-1898., (421)
      - Sargent, Epes, 1813-1880. 2 letters; 1879-1880., (422)
      - Sawyer, Walter Leon, 1862-1915. 1 letter; 1900., (423)
        Schock, Georg, pseud. See Loose, Katharine Riegel, 1877-.
      - Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942. 1 letter; 1900., (424)
      - Schurz, Carl, 1829-1906. 6 letters; 1876-1906., (425)
      - Scott, Frank H. 2 letters; 1891., (426)
      - Scribner, Charles, 1854-1930. 3 letters; 1885-1900., (427)
      - Scudder, Horace Elisha, 1838-1902. 10 letters; 1867-1900., (428)
      - Shairp, John Campbell, 1819-1885. 1 letter; 1879., (429)
      - Shaler, Nathaniel Southgate, 1841-1906. 1 letter; 1880., (430)
      - Sharp, William, 1855-1905. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (431)
      - Shepard, Elliott Fitch, 1833-1893. 1 letter; 1891., (432)
      - Sheppard, William Ludlow, 1833-1912. 1 letter; 1886., (433)
      - Sherman, Frank Dempster, 1860-1916. 1 letter; 1885., (434)
      - Sherman, John, 1823-1900. 1 letter; 1884., (435)
      - Sherwood, Mary Elizabeth (Wilson) 1830-1903. 3 letters; 1880 [n.d.]., (436)
      - Smalley, George Washburn, 1833-1916. 3 letters; 1883-1886., (437)
      - Smith, Francis Hopkinson, 1838-1915. 2 letters; [n.d.]., (438)
      - Smith, Goldwin, 1823-1910. 9 letters; [1869]-1880., (439)
        No. 2 with letter from J.S. C[lark] to W.D. Howells.
      - Smith, Orlando Jay, 1842-1908. 1 letter; 1887., (440)
      - Smith, Richard. 1 letter; 1866., (441)
      - Smith, Roswell, 1829-1892. 16 letters; 1881-1886., (442)
        No. 4 with note by R[ichard] W[atson] G[ilder].
        No. 16 signed by another hand.
      - Smith, S.M. 1 letter; 1861., (443)
      - Smith, Susan E. 1 letter; 1875., (444)
      - Smith, William Henry, 1833-1896. 1 telegram; 1876., (445)
      - Smyth, Albert Henry, 1863-1907. 1 letter; 1895., (446)
      - Sothern, Edward Hugh, 1859-1933. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (447)
      - Speakman, C.A. 1 letter; 1898., (448)
      - Spofford, Ainsworth Rand, 1825-1908. 1 letter; 1876., (449)
      - Spofford, Harriet Elizabeth (Prescott), 1835-1921. 6 letters; 1879-1919 [n.d.]., (450)
      - Stafford, Alphonso Orenzo, 1871-. 1 letter; 1896., (451)
      - Stanhope, Lucy Constance (Egerton). 1 letter; [n.d.]., (452)
      - Starey, A.B. 2 letters; 1889-1890., (453)
      - Stedman, Edmund Clarence, 1833-1908. 47 letters; 1861-1907 [n.d.]., (454)
        Nos. 7, 8, 9, 13, 17, 19, 25, 26, 38 publ. in Laura Stedman and George M. Gould, Life and letters of Edmund Clarence Stedman.
      - Stephen, Sir Leslie, 1832-1904. 5 letters; 1879-1890., (455)
        Stepniak, Sergius, pseud. See Kravchinskii, Sergei Mikhailovich, 1851-1895.
      - Stevenson, Robert Louis, 1850-1894. 3 letters; 1893 [n.d.]., (456)
        Nos. 1 and 2 with typed copies.
      - Stillman, William James, 1828-1901. 8 letters; 1862-1896., (457)
      - Stockton, Frank Richard, 1834-1902. 6 letters; 1883-1900., (458)
      - Stoddard, Charles Warren, 1843-1909. 11 letters; 1872-1903., (459)
      - Stoddard, Elizabeth Drew (Barstow) 1823-1902. 11 letters; [n.d.]., (460)
        No. 1 with letter from Richard Henry Stoddard to W.D. Howells.
      - Stoddard, Richard Henry, 1825-1903. 11 letters; 1865-1895 [n.d.]., (461)
        No. 10 incomplete.
      - Stoker, Bram, 1847-1912. 1 letter; 1884., (462)
      - Stone, Herbert Stuart, 1871-. 1 letter; [n.d.]., (463)
      - Story, William Wetmore, 1819-1895. 6 letters; 1875-1879., (464)
      - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, 1811-1896. 8 letters; 1878 [n.d.]., (465)
      - Strachey, John St. Loe, 1860-1927. 4 letters; 1903-1905., (466)
      - Strauss, S.J. 1 letter; 1885., (467)
      - Sulzberger, Cyrus Leo, 1858-1932. 2 letters; 1885., (468)
      - Sutherland, Millicent (Francis) Leveson-Gower, duchess of, 1867-. 1 letter; 1908., (469)
      - Symon, C. 2 letters; 1919., (470)
      - Taft, William Howard, pres. U.S., 1857-1930. 1 letter; 1912., (471)
      - Talcott, Henry. 1 letter; 1861., (472)
        Signed by Henry Talcott and others.
      - Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946. 4 letters; 1914-1919., (473)
      - Tauchnitz, [], freiherr von. 5 letters; 1879-1901., (474)
        No. 5 is a contract between W.D. Howells and the firm of Bernhard Tauchnitz, Leipzig.
      - Taylor, Bayard, 1825-1878. 11 letters; 1862-1878., (475)
      - Taylor, J.V. Elliott. 1 letter; 1910., (476)
      - Teuffel, Blanche Willis (Howard) von, 1847-1898. 1 letter; 1887., (477)
      - Thaxter, Celia (Laighton) 1835-1894. 13 letters; 1873-1874 [n.d.]., (478)